

## **MATTHEW ADENYO**

Address: AP19 Tufohene Nyame Street (WR-758-5163),

Beposo – Shama, Western Region, Ghana.

Email: adenyomatthew@gmail.com Phone: +233 24 789 8793

LinkedIn: <a href="mailto:linkedin.com/in/matth-adenyo">linkedIn: linkedin.com/in/matth-adenyo</a>

Portfolio: <a href="https://www.datacamp.com/portfolio/Matth-Adenyo">https://www.datacamp.com/portfolio/Matth-Adenyo</a>

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

A skilled teacher, researcher, leader and data analyst with experience in teaching, researching, leadership, collecting, organizing, interpreting and disseminating various types of statistical figures. Energetic presenter and confident communicator with the ability to circulate information in a way that is clear, efficient and beneficial for all end users. Creative in finding solutions to problems and determining modifications for optimal use of organizational data.

### **SKILLS & INTEREST**

Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint, Power BI), Latex, R, Python, SQL, Research, Teaching, Leadership, Attention to Detail, Critical Thinking, Problem-Solving, Graphic Design (Adobe Photoshop), Data Science/Analysis, Data Visualization, etc.

### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

### **Cognifyz Technologies**

Nagpur, IN

Data Science Intern [Remote]

*March* 2024 – *April* 2024

- Assisted in developing data-driven solutions by analyzing restaurant datasets.
- Assisted in collecting, cleaning, and interpreting data.

### Learners Platform (https://www.learnersplatform.com/)

Accra, GH

Mathematics Tutor [Full-Time]

March 2023 - March 2024

An e-learning platform, known for its interactive and innovative learning support for Nursing Training Students, High School Students and Basic School Students across Africa.

- Provided Mathematics tutorials to Senior High School and Junior High School Students.
- Provided solutions to Senior High School and Junior High School Mathematics past questions.

### **University of Mines and Technology (UMaT)**

Tarkwa, GH

Teaching/Research Assistant [Full-Time]

November 2021 – October 2022

- Assisted lecturers with research works
- Assisted lecturers with classroom instructions, exams, record keeping, and other miscellaneous projects
- Tutored and mentored undergraduate students in Mathematical Programming, Linear Algebra, Calculus and Numerical Methods & Scientific Computing
- Conducted tutorials and review sections
- Prepared presentations for lecturers
- Marked assignments and tests

#### Shama District Assembly (SDA)

Shama, GH

Internship (Revenue Office) [Full-Time]

June – August 2018

- Quickly learned new skills and applied them to daily tasks, improving efficiency and productivity.
- Carried out day-to-day duties accurately and efficiently.
- Demonstrated respect, friendliness and willingness to help wherever needed.
- Assisted in field monitoring and inspection.
- Prepared permits for individuals and organizations.
- Assessed buildings for property rate bills and revenue collection.

**Nata Academy Preparatory School** 

Beposo, GH

- Taught all classes of the school level curriculum from JHS 1-3 Mathematics and Integrated Science.
- Administered feedback to students using positive reinforcement techniques to encourage and build confidence.
- Participated in professional development activities to improve tutorial skills and grow cultural competence and reflection skills.
- Participated in training classes to improve tutoring practices and learn new tutoring techniques.
- Implemented listening and questioning strategies to diagnose student needs and monitor progress.
- Prepared and delivered regular lessons, prepared workshops for staff, and conducted tutorial sessions and classes where necessary.

#### **PROJECTS**

## • Game Analysis: Decoding Gaming Behaviour | SQL

Conducted an in-depth analysis of gaming behaviour using SQL, extracting and analyzing large datasets to uncover player trends and patterns. Used advanced analytical techniques to decode player engagement and performance metrics.

## • Restaurant Data Analysis | R

Analyzed a restaurant dataset to explore insights and build predictive models. Cleaned, processed and analyzed the datasets to identify key trends in customer behaviour, menu preferences and most common price range. Implemented statistical models and visualizations to provide actionable insights for optimizing menu offerings, pricing strategies, and operational efficiency. Build four different predictive models to predict rating of restaurants and compare their performance.

### • Pizza Sales Analysis | Power BI

Executed end-to-end analysis of pizza sales data using Power BI, showcasing proficiency in data extraction, transformation, and visualization and employing advanced data visualization techniques to identify key trends and insights such as top and bottom performers by revenue, by quantity and by orders and customer's favourite pizza type and size.

### **EDUCATION**

University of Mines and Technology (UMaT)	Tarkwa, GH			
BSc Mathematics (Second Class Upper)	Graduation Date: November 2021			
Ghana Sec/Tech School (G.S.T.S) WASSCE (General Science Option)	<b>Takoradi, GH</b> <i>Graduation Date: March</i> 2016			
AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS				
Internship Completion Certificate, Cognifyz Technologies	April 2024			
• Statement of Accomplishment, Data Analyst in SQL – DataCamp [Credential]	January 2024			

•	internship Completion Certificate, Cognity2 Technologies	April 2024
•	Statement of Accomplishment, Data Analyst in SQL – DataCamp [Credential]	January 2024
•	Statement of Accomplishment, Data Scientist with R – DataCamp [Credential]	October 2023
•	Certified Associate Data Scientist – DataCamp [Credential]	September 2023
•	UNESCO-India-Africa Hackathon Finalist	November 2022
•	Certificate of Completion, Power BI Fundamentals – Festman Learning Hub	September 2022
•	Certificate of Completion, Introduction to Data Science in Python: Coursera [Credential]	February 2022
•	Certificate of Completion, Data Scientist's Toolbox: Coursera [Credential]	November 2021
•	IBM Cognitive Class, Data Science Orientation: Coursera [Credential]	November 2021
•	IBM Cognitive Class, Data Science Methodology: Coursera [Credential]	December 2021
•	IBM Cognitive Class, Tools for Data Science: Coursera [Credential]	December 2021
•	Certificate of Achievement, SAS Programming 1: Essentials [Credential]	December 2020

### **ACTIVITIES & AFFILIATIONS**

Association of Mathematics Students (Uni. of Mines and Tech.), President	November 2020 – July 2021
Ghana Methodist Students' Union (Uni. of Mines and Tech.), President	April 2019 – July 2021

#### REFEREE

### **Dr Henry Otoo**

Head, Mechanical Engineering Department University of Mines and Technology (UMaT), Tarkwa hotoo@umat.edu.gh | +233 54 141 4406

# Dr. Kofi Agyarko

Lecturer, Department of Mathematical Sciences University of Mines and Technology (UMaT), Tarkwa kagyarko@umat.edu.gh | +233 24 617 3533